it's such a humbling and honoring
experience for me to welcome and to
thank me chan for all the years and
years of service she have done for the
asian community
i still remember when both of us were
young and poor
we were hustling she didn't have an
office and i think i just have a one
cubicle as an office and then she
started the cubicle
and then we were calling mr tim hagen
for money i mean you name it we have
done it together
and i always ask her why are you doing
all this and so here we are after all
those years of friendship
and i'm just so proud and honored to be
able to give her this award for today
i was honored to be in an all group
class of the hall of fame and being very
very good friends with dan and debbie
and mom hansen and now i welcome you to
our club
and being a long long time friends we
were young at one time and young and
single and poor now we're happily
married and all our old friends are
still standing and working together what
an honor
thank you so much margaret thank you
thank you
hi everyone this is michael bien i'm the
former ceo for asian services and action
inc i'd like to take a moment today to
congratulate me chen for being inducted
into the international hall of fame
may chan deserves this award if not more
for all the work that she's done in the
many years in northeast ohio
i know may through my time at asia in my
early career when she provided a safe
space for me to grow and thrive
and today i am the executive director
for asian counseling and referral
service here in seattle washington an
organization that provides critical
services as well as advocacy for our
immigrant and refugee communities
both may and cf continue to provide
great support to this community in ohio
and through their generosity and their
ongoing commitment to this community we
see
that asians and pacific islanders and
immigrants and refugees thrive
and are able to find a place
they call home in ohio
again congratulations may on receiving
this award
and hi from seattle take care bye-bye
what a great honor it is for me to
receive the 2020 cleveland international
hall of fame award today
i always saw myself as an ordinary woman
simply trying to do the right and just
thing
but i do want to thank profusely
cleveland international hall of fame
selection committee for this honor
i believe this prestigious
award
should be rightfully be shared with
immigrants
and refugees whom i have the honor
of
helping and serving
i'm constantly humbled and moved by
their matchless resiliency
great sacrifices endurance of
unspeakable pain
and remarkable adjustment to challenging
circumstances to realize their hopes and
dreams for themselves and their families
my work was simply to help them navigate
through unfamiliar terrain
and overcome barriers in america to
reach their goals
my journey with them has been fulfilling
inspiring and great joy
in the early 30s when my parents came to
study in america they were inspired by
their thought-provoking professors
witnessed boundless opportunities to
create and succeed and felt much warmth
and support from fellow americans during
their stay
after returning to china and hong kong
they were convinced america was the
place where their children would thrive
and succeed
my siblings and i will remain forever
grateful for the sacrifices they made
for our coming to america
my life's work and passion are to help
and serve immigrants and refugees and
would not come to fruition were it not
for america's kind and big heart for the
displaced
oppressed and marginalized in our world
service compassion generosity and human
rights characterize the strengths of
this country
therefore i would remain forever
grateful to this country for realizing
my dream
to improve the quality of life for
immigrants and refugees to become fully
contributing and patriotic american
citizens
first i want to thank my husband cf chan
for remaining gainfully employed to
support and allow my working at asian
services in action
and i personally want to thank many men
and women
at asian services in action over its 25
years in northeast ohio whose dedication
and commitment to the wellness of the
community have been inspiring and
exemplary
specifically michael beyond former ceo
of asia
elaine zhao present ceo of asia mao
mauvu
navin geheke dr mary d
susan wong
barbara snyder
hayek b lam
kim helms mingo and kyle lismore whose
loyalty and contribution have helped
asian services become a meaningful and
impactful presence for immigrants and
refugees in northeast ohio
without them my vision to serve the
community would not have been a reality
my virgin hope is that we must continue
to foster and nurture men and women
young adults and youth in our immigrant
and refugee communities to be a
meaningful
voice
and leaders
northeast ohio can provide resources and
opportunities to realize this most
important goal
our own immigrant communities must
specifically engage and rise above
preoccupation with our own economic and
educational achievements we must learn
to incorporate altruism compassion and
philanthropy in our lives
finally during these difficult times
from the pandemic
racism and political divide
we must re-establish our faith in one
another
revert to our country's core values and
continue to welcome and be inclusive of
immigrants and refugees who hold great
promise
growth and strength for america